Hello and welcome back.
So in this section we will discuss about the shared library, add on.
Okay, So basically the purpose of shared library add on is to, uh, to share some of the libraries
with your embedded device to, to your vendor or maybe to an external partner.
Okay.
So in case, for example, in a real world scenario, for example, if you are working for an OEM like
Samsung or some other company, then there might be a lot of vendors, okay, who might be producing
some softwares or maybe something else for you.
Okay.
So in case if you want to provide a hardware abstraction layer to your partner or an external company,
then what you can do is you can create a shared library, add on and embed or attach that within your
SDK and pass it on to the vendor.
So what you can do exactly is that you can host your shared library, add on somewhere in the somewhere
in the web and you are your partner actually can just use it in the update sites.
Okay.
So we will try to do a demo.
We'll just first go through the steps required to create a shared library, add on, and then in the
next tutorial we will do, uh, a practical session on shared library add on.
Okay, so, so these are the steps basically you need to follow to create a shared library.
Okay.
So basically, uh, the, so the first step is like you can refer to the sample device which is already
provided within Aosp.
So in Aosp if you go to.
Device folder and there is a folder called sample.
So inside the sample there is an add on implementation.
So the easiest way of doing it is like, just take a copy of this.
So this is basically your device and then include your library under the apps and edit the Android dot.
MK Not here.
So android.mk and manifest dot in all those stuffs here and also here within the apps you might be putting
your library and just update the update the Android dot.
So for example in this case, so it says the normal Android dot.
MK So you basically need to update that.
So we'll have a look at that in the next tutorial in the practical session.
So for now, just keep in mind that you can always refer to the sample device or you can create it on
your own, Okay?
And then building is quite straightforward.
So what you need to do is set up environment setup and then just make and the product.
So this is the product and your add on name and then hyphen SDK add on.
Okay, so this is the command which you need to execute to build an add on.
Okay.
So once that is built, once the SDK is built, you will get the SDK add on at this location.
So in this location, so to make it available for the developers, either you can share it within your
local internet or maybe local web server, or maybe you can put it on the on a Web site, on a web server
and share the link to your developer so that they can add include the add on in their Android studio.
So, uh, so I think for theory part, I think that's it for this session.
So we will look into a practical session in the next tutorial.
Thank you.